"Thank you" is a very polite thing to say when you are given something, and this is particularly important when receiving an award at a prestigious ceremony.
当你收到别人赠予的东西时，说一句“谢谢”是很有礼貌的做法，尤其是在声望颇高的颁奖典礼上领奖时，这句话就显得尤为重要。
But if you're one of the lucky winners, "thank you" is just the start of the most important acceptance speech of your life.
但如果你是幸运的获奖者之一，那么“谢谢”仅仅是你人生中最重要的获奖感言的开场白。
Film, TV and music award ceremonies are all about the acceptance speeches – they are an art form in their own right.
影视和音乐颁奖典礼的核心看点之一就是获奖感言——这些感言本身就是一种艺术形式。
They are a chance for an actor or performer to publicly thank people who've helped them.
对演员或表演者来说，这是一个公开感谢那些曾帮助过自己的人的机会。
In this year's BAFTAs, Letitia Wright even thanked God for her EE Rising Star award in an emotional acceptance speech.
在今年的英国电影学院奖颁奖典礼上，莱蒂蒂娅·赖特在饱含深情的获奖感言中，甚至感谢了上帝，为自己赢得了英国电影学院奖新星奖。
Speeches are also used as a platform to make a political statement or just to raise someone's profile – so it's important to get the words right.
获奖感言也可以作为发表政治声明或提升个人知名度的平台——因此，措辞恰当至关重要。
And these words have to be delivered in a short amount of time.
而且这些话必须在短时间内说完。
For example, at this year's Oscars, nominees have only 90 seconds from finding out they've won to finishing their speech.
例如，在今年的奥斯卡颁奖典礼上，提名者从得知获奖到结束感言，只有90秒的时间。
John Bailey, president of the Academy, has told them they should "get up there and keep speeches brief."
美国电影艺术与科学学院主席约翰·贝利告诉他们，应该“上台后保持感言简洁”。
When the clock is ticking, it's hard to say everything you want.
当时间一分一秒流逝时，很难把所有想说的话都讲出来。
Weeping can waste time; bumbling costs valuable seconds.
哭泣会浪费时间，结结巴巴的表述也会耗费宝贵的时间。
Experts in the field say it's important to be personable, heartfelt and to speak like you're talking to a friend.
该领域的专家表示，感言要亲切自然、真挚诚恳，就像和朋友聊天一样。
At the 2019 Golden Globes, Olivia Colman was named the best actress for her role as Queen Anne in The Favourite and gave an endearingly excited speech that ended with her holding up her trophy and sending a message to her family: "Ed and the kids - look!
在2019年的金球奖颁奖典礼上，奥利维娅·科尔曼凭借《宠儿》中安妮女王一角荣获最佳女主角，她发表了一段可爱又激动的感言，最后举起奖杯对家人喊话：“埃德和孩子们——快看！
Yay!"
太棒啦！”
You would expect an actor to be eloquent and able to perform on stage in front of an audience.
人们通常会认为演员口才出众，能够在舞台上面对观众从容表现。
But for others, such as sports people, it can be more awkward.
但对其他人而言，比如运动员，在这种场合发言可能会更尴尬。
When Japan's Naomi Osaka won this year's Australian Open final, she said "Sorry, public speaking isn't my strong point so I hope I can get through this…
日本选手大坂直美赢得今年澳大利亚网球公开赛冠军后就表示：“抱歉，公开演讲不是我的强项，希望我能顺利说完……
I read notes before this but I still forgot what I was meant to say."
我之前还看了笔记，但还是忘了原本想说的话。”
Preparation is key.
充分准备是关键。
It's important to make notes that remind you to thank people, say some words of wisdom, and win over the audience.
列好提纲很重要，它能提醒你要感谢哪些人、说几句至理名言，以及如何打动观众。
But if you've got nothing to say, accept your award graciously then get off stage before the music starts playing again – just remember to say "thank you"!
但如果你实在没什么可说的，那就优雅地接过奖杯，在背景音乐再次响起前走下舞台——切记要说一句“谢谢”！